Guide to the Helen Magill White papers, 1865-1938
White, Helen Magill papers, 1865-1938
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Helen Magill White papers, 1865-1938.
4107
Helen Magill White 1853-1944.
7.6 cubic ft., 7 reels of microfilm (3 negative & 4 positive)
Correspondence, microfilm, notebooks, papers, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes Magill family correspondence; correspondence between Helen and friends; papers pertaining to Helen's work as principal of Howard Institute; letters between Helen and A. D. White before and after their marriage; correspondence with White's children; correspondence with Karin, Helen's daughter; and microfilm of diaries.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Helen Magill completed her Ph.D. in Greek in 1877 at Boston University. She served as principal of the Howard Collegiate Institute, a girls' school in West Bridgewater, Massachusetts; taught briefly at Evelyn College, a short-lived women's annex to Princeton University; and taught physical geography at Brooklyn High School. In September 1887, while presenting a paper at the annual meeting of the American Social Science Association, she met Andrew Dickson White, a friend of her father, Edward Hicks Magill, then president of Swarthmore College. This meeting was the beginning of a friendship which led to marriage in 1890. She administered their household and traveled with White to Russia and Germany. After White's death in 1918, she lived abroad and in Ithaca, New York, and then retired to Kittery Point, Maine, where she died in 1944.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes Magill family correspondence, 1865-90; correspondence between Helen and a childhood friend, Eva Channing; letters and other papers pertaining to Helen's work as principal of Howard Institute; letters between Helen and A. D. White before and after their marriage; letters to Helen from friends; correspondence with White's children from his first marriage; correspondence with Karin, Helen's daughter; and microfilm of 19 diaries, 1867-1933. Also includes correspondence of A. D. White; notebooks, bills, and receipts, invitations to and menus from diplomatic affairs, Christmas cards, and a diplomatic case.
SUBJECTS
Names:
White, Helen Magill, 1853-1944.; Channing, Eva.; Magill, Edward Hicks.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; White, Karin Andreevna.; Howard Collegiate Institute.
Subjects:
Women--Education.; Women in education.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Diaries available on microfilm.
Cambridge correspondence (Box 2, Folders 8-16) available on microfilm.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence and Papers
Box 1-28
Series II. Diaries and Cambridge correspondence on Microfilm
Reels 1-4 (positive)
Series III. Museum items
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence and Papers
  - Correspondence, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - To Helen Magill from Eva Channing, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Helen Magill to Eva Channing, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Helen Magill - Eva Channing, Jan. 1870 - Apr. 1870 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Helen Magill - Eva Channing, May 1870 - June 1870 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Helen Magill - Eva Channing, July 1870 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Helen Magill - Eva Channing, Aug. 1870 - Sept. 1870 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - To Helen Magill from Eva Channing, Oct. 1870 - Dec. 1870 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1871 - June 1871 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, July 1871 - Dec. 1871 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1872 - Feb. 1872 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1872 - Apr. 1872 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, May 1872 - June 1872 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, July 1872 - Aug. 1872 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1872 - Oct. 1872 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1872 - Dec. 1872 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1873 - Feb. 1873 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1873 - Apr. 1873 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, May 1873 - June 1873 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, July 1873 - Aug. 1873 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1873 - Oct. 1873 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1873 - Dec. 1873 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1874 - June 1874 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, July 1874 - Sept. 1874 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1874 - Dec. 1874 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Helen Magill - Eva Channing, Jan. 1875 - Feb. 1875 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1875 - May 1875 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Helen Magill to Eva Channing, June 1875 - July 1875 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Helen Magill to Eva Channing, Aug. 1875 - Nov. 1875 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Helen Magill - Eva Channing, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Correspondence, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Correspondence, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1881 - Apr. 1881 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, May 1881 - Dec. 1881 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1882 - Apr. 1882 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, May 1882 - Oct. 1882 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1883 - June 1883 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, July 1883 - Dec. 1883 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1884 - Mar. 1884 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1884 - June 1884 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, July 1884 - Dec. 1884 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1885 - June 1885 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, July 1885 - Dec. 1885 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1886 - June 1886 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, July 1886 - Dec. 1886 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1887 - Feb. 1887 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1887 - Apr. 1887 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, May 1887 - July 1887 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1887 - Oct. 1887 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1887 - Dec. 1887 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1888 - Feb. 1888 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1888 - Apr. 1888 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, May 1888 - June 1888 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, July 1888 - Aug. 1888 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1888 - Oct. 1888 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1888 - Dec. 1888 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1889 - Feb. 1889 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1889 - Apr. 1889 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May 1889 - June 1889 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, July 1889 - Aug. 1889 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1889 - Oct. 1889 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1889 - Dec. 1889 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1890 - Feb. 1890 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1890 - Apr. 1890 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, May 1890 - June 1890 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, July 1890 - Aug. 1890 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1890 - Oct. 1890 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1890 - Dec. 1890 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence fragment, letter missing page, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1891 - Feb. 1891 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1891 - Apr. 1891 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, May 1891 - July 1891 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1891 - Sept. 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1891 - Dec. 1891 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1892 - Mar. 1892 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1892 - May 1892 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, June 1892 - July 1892 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1892 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1892 - Dec. 1892 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1893 - Apr. 1893 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, May 1893 - July 1893 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1893 - Oct. 1893 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1893 - Dec. 1893 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1894 - Mar. 1894 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1894 - Aug. 1894 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1894 - Dec. 1894 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1895 - Mar. 1895 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1895 - June 1895 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, July 1895 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1895 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1895 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1895 - Dec. 1895 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1896 - Mar. 1896 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1896 - July 1896 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1896 - Sept. 1896 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1896 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1896 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1896 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1897 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1897 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1897 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1897 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, May 1897 - Dec. 1897 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1898 - Mar. 1898 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1898 - July 1898 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1898 - Sept. 1898 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1898 - Nov. 1898 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1899 - Sept. 1899 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1899 - Dec. 1899 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence fragments, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1900 - Dec. 1900 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, May 1900 - June 1900 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, July 1900 - Aug. 1900 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Sept. 1900 - Dec. 1900 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Fragments, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1901 - July 1901 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1901 - Sept. 1901 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1901 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1901 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1901 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Fragments, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1902 - Feb. 1902 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1902 - May 1902 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, June 1902 - Dec. 1902 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1903 - Feb. 1903 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1903 - Apr. 1903 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, May 1903 - July 1903 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1903 - Dec. 1903 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1904 - Mar. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, May 1904 - June 1904 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, July 1904 - Sept. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1904 - Dec. 1904 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1905 - Feb. 1905 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1905 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1905 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, May 1905 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, June 1905 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, July 1905 - Aug. 1905 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1905 - Oct. 1905 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1905 - Dec. 1905 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1906 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1906 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1906 - Apr. 1906 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, May 1906 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, June 1906 - July 1906 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1906 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1906 - Oct. 1906 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1906 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1906 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1907 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1907 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1907 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1907 - July 1907 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1907 - Oct. 1907 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1907 - Dec. 1907 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1908 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1908 - Mar. 1908 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1908 - June 1908 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1908 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1908 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1908 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1908 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1908 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1909 - Mar. 1909 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, May 1909 - Aug. 1909 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1909 - Dec. 1909 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Edith Roosevelt & Hiram Corson letters (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Fragments, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1910 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1910 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Mar. 1910 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1910 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, May 1910 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, June 1910 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, July 1910 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Titchener letters, July 28, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1910 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1910 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1910 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1910 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Dec. 1910 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Fragments, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1911 - Mar. 1911 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1911 - July 1911 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1911 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1911 - Dec. 1911 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 17-18)
  - Damaged letter, Aug. 28, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1912 - Dec. 1912 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Jan. 1913 - June 1913 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, July 1913 - Oct. 1913 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 1913 - Dec. 1913 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Fragments, 1913 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1914 - Dec. 1914 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1915 - July 1915 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1915 - Dec. 1915 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Drafts of letters, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - A. D. White drafts, 1915 - 1917 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1916 - Mar. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Apr. 1916 - Dec. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Drafts and letters, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - A. D. White letters (drafts), Jan. 1917 - May 1917 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Drafts of letters, June 1917 - Dec. 1917 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1918 - Dec. 1918 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - A. D. White drafts, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Condolences - telegrams, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Condolences, 1918 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - To A. D. White & Helen Magill White about Ruth White Ferry, 1918-1921 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Documents Ruth White Ferry, 1922-1923 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 1919 - June 1919 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, July 1919 - Dec. 1919 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1920 - Dec. 1920 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1921 - July 1921 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1921 - Dec. 1921 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 1922 - July 1922 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1922 - Dec. 1922 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 193 - Dec. 1923 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Birthday letters to Helen Magill White, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White & Karin White in will (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Fragments, 1882-1901 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Fragments, 1890s (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Damaged letter, May 27, 1902 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Fragments, 1907-1908 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Fragments, 1910 - 1922 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Fragments, Undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence from Karin, Undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence from Helen Magill to Eva Channing, Undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Titled "Autographs" (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - From rolled letters (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence Helen Magill White, Undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Birthday and Christmas cards, 1933-1934 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Helen Magill White - Christmas cards, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
  - Helen Magill White birthday cards, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Photographic cards (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Handpainted Christmas card by "Miss Bryant" (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Christmas cards to Karin at Belleayre, Ithaca, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Helen Magill White birthday cards, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Christmas cards, notes & telegrams, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Helen Magill White birthday telegrams, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Christmas calendar, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Christmas cards to Helen and Karin, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
  - Cards to Helen Magill White and Karin White, 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Damaged cards, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Christmas cards to Helen and Karin, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Christmas cards to Karin, Undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Christmas cards to Karin and Helen Magill White, Undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Christmas cards (Box 15, Folder 20-27)
  - Berlin Club address, etc. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Capital Punishment Helen Magill White, 1872 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Helen Magill White - a reply to "Women's Book of Wages" (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript by Helen Magill White (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Writings (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Draft of a paper on learning Latin, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Helen Magill manuscript on birds (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript writings by Helen Magill, 1877 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Writings by Helen Magill (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Writings by Helen Magill White (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript writings by Helen Magill White and others (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Helen G. Ferry paper (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Diary notes (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Helen Magill White diary, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Helen Magill - information about other colleges (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Helen Magill notes - postgraduate study, 1882 (Box 16, Folder 17-18)
  - Helen Magill White notes (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Helen Magill White notes (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Helen Magill White notes (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Helen Magill White notes (Box 17, Folder 2-4)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Notes & fragments (Box 17, Folder 6-10)
  - Miscellaneous, notes & clippings (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, notebooks (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Invitations & menus (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
  - Programs (Box 18, Folder 4-6)
  - A. D. White - miscellaneous, 1916-1918 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Testimony Battle of Chancellorville, 1865 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Pattern (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Edward Magill - bills, 1884-1885 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Karin White, 1908-1909 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Karin White, 1910-1911 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Bills & receipts (Box 19, Folder 4-6)
  - Howard Institute (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Howard Institute, 1883-1887 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Account book, 1871 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Document, 1777 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Legal documents (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Passports (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Louis Agassiz Fuertes (watercolor) (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - 1902 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Sketches (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Photographs (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Recipes (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Pamphlets, brochures, etc. (Box 19, Folder 18-20)
  - Advertisement brochures, handouts, broadsides (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous clippings & articles (Box 19, Folder 22-23)
  - Typescript article (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Reprint on flowers (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Red Cross Stamps, 1 stamp, 1916-1917 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Postcards (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - NYC maps, ship layouts (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Business cards and calling cards (Box 19, Folder 29-30)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
  - Draft of a talk (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Notebook (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 2 notebooks (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
  - Notebook (Box 21, Folder 5-8)
  - 2 notebooks (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Book - Iliad (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 10 volumes of notebooks (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 2 books (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 15 volumes of notebooks (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 2 notebooks of dried plants (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - 3 notebooks (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Notebook (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - 2 briefcases (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Helen Magill White from Emmy Garrison, 1890 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Helen Magill White to A. D. White, 1892 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 10 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1 letter to A. D. White, 1893 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 22 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1893 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - 13 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1 letter from Helen Magill White, 1893 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - 11 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 3 letters from others, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - 20 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - 14 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - 9 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1 letter from Helen Magill White, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - 11 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - 3 letters and 1 telegram from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - 1 letter from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1895 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - 12 letters from A. D. White to Helen Magill White, 1896 (Box 25, Folder 13)